import 'dart:math';

class Flashcard {
  final bool TF_flag;
  final String question;
  final int index;
  final String option1;
  final String option2;
  final String option3;
  final String option4;
  final String answer;

  Flashcard({required this.TF_flag,required this.question, required this.index,required this.option1,required this.option2,required this.option3,
  required this.option4,required this.answer});

}
//var currval, prevval = 0;

List<Flashcard> qlist = [

  Flashcard(index:0,
  question:'Which of the following is not true about fourth generation computers ',
  option1: 'It used VLSI', 
  option2:'It was smaller, reliable and engergy efficient',
  option3:'It was extremely powerful and could process millions of instructions',
  option4:'It was based on Artificial Intelligence',
  answer:'It was based on Artificial Intelligence',
  TF_flag: false),
  Flashcard(index:1,
  question:'Which of the following is not a limitation of a computer?  ',
  option1:'Zero IQ',
  option2:'No Heuristics',
  option3:'Lack of decision making',
  option4: 'No secondary storage',
  answer:'No secondary storage',
   TF_flag: false),
  Flashcard(index:2,
  question:'RAM is a ',
  option1:'Primary memory',
  option2:'secondary memory',
  option3:'tertiary memory',
  option4:'None of these',
  answer:'Primary memory',
   TF_flag: false),
  Flashcard(index:3,
  question:'ROM is a ',
  option1:'Primary memory',
  option2:'secondary memory',
  option3:'tertiary memory',
  option4:'None of these',
  answer:'secondary memory',
   TF_flag: false),
  Flashcard(index:4,
  question:'Which among these is volatile in nature? ',
  option1:'RAM',
  option2:'ROM',
  option3:'Hard disk',
  option4:'CD',
  answer:'RAM',
   TF_flag: false),
  Flashcard(index:5,
  question:'BIOS stands for ',
  option1:'Basic Internal Output System',
  option2:'Basic In Out System',
  option3:'Basic Input Output System',
  option4:'Basic In Output System',
  answer:'Basic Input Output System',
   TF_flag: false), 
  Flashcard(index:6,
  question:'Which among these is true about ROM ',
  option1:'ROM is volatile in nature',
  option2:'Example of ROM is CD',
  option3:'ROM contains pre-recorded instructions that can only be read',
  option4:'We can perform write operation in ROM',
  answer:'ROM contains pre-recorded instructions that can only be read',
   TF_flag: false),
  Flashcard(index:7,
   TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which among these is true about pen drive ',
  option1:'Pen drives are very large in size',
  option2:'Pen drives are secondary storage memory',
  option3:'Pen drives can only be read and not written to',
  option4:'None',
  answer:'Pen drives are secondary storage memory'),
  Flashcard(index:8,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'____________ contains a basic set of instructions called BIOS which starts the Operating system',
  option1:'RAM',
  option2:'ROM',
  option3:'BluRay',
  option4:'Hard disk',
  answer:'ROM'),
Flashcard(index:9,
   TF_flag: false,
  question:'1024 Gigabytes = 1 __________',
  option1:'Petabyte',
  option2:'Byte',
  option3:'KiloByte',
  option4:'TeraByte',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'TeraByte'),
Flashcard(index:10,
   TF_flag: false,
  question:'This is circular in shape, can hold more data than a CD',
  option1:'DVD',
  option2:'Floppy Disk',
  option3:'Hard disk',
  option4:'RAM',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'DVD'),
Flashcard(index:11,
   TF_flag: false,
  question:'The smallest unit of measuring computer memory',
  option1:'Petabyte',
  option2:'Byte',
  option3:'KiloByte',
  option4:'Bit',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Bit'),
  Flashcard(index:12,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'1 Byte = _______ bits',
  option1:'8',
  option2:'16',
  option3:'1024',
  option4:'1',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'8'),
  Flashcard(index:13,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which of these is true about secondary storage devices?',
  option1:'Secondary storage devices are Read only',
  option2:'Secondary storage devices are volatile in nature',
  option3:'Secondary Storage devices can store large amounts of data',
  option4:'RAM is an example of Secondary storage device ',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Secondary Storage devices can store large amounts of data'),
  Flashcard(index:14,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'The first generation computers used _______',
  option1:'vacuum tubes',
  option2:'supercomputers',
  option3:'transistors',
  option4:'keyboards',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'vacuum tubes'),
  Flashcard(index:15,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'The Difference Engine was designed by  _______',
  option1:'John Napier',
  option2:'Blaise Pascal',
  option3:'Charles Babbage',
  option4:'John Mauchly',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Charles Babbage'),
  Flashcard(index:16,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'The ability to learn from past mistakes is called  _______',
  option1:'Zero IQ',
  option2:'Heuristics',
  option3:'Decision Making',
  option4:'Faster Communication',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Heuristics'),
  Flashcard(index:17,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'The branch of computer science that deals with making the computers think and take decisions like human beings is called  _______',
  option1:'Artificial Intelligence',
  option2:'Arithmetic Operation',
  option3:'Integrated Circuits',
  option4:'Computer Engineering',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Artificial Intelligence'),
  Flashcard(index:18,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'The second generation computers used ',
  option1:'Vacuum tubes',
  option2:'Transistors',
  option3:'CPU',
  option4:'Radio',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Transistors'),
  Flashcard(index:19,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'_____________ is an example of first generation computers ',
  option1:'Macbook',
  option2:'Laptop',
  option3:'EDVAC',
  option4:'IBM 360',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'EDVAC'),
  Flashcard(index:20,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'The third generation computers used ___________ ',
  option1:'Vacuum tubes',
  option2:'Transistors',
  option3:'Integrated Circuits',
  option4:'Artificial Intelligence',
  answer:'Integrated Circuits'),
  Flashcard(index:21,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which of these commands brings the turtle to the center of the screen? ',
  option1:'PRINT',
  option2:'HOME',
  option3:'SETH',
  option4:'PENERASE',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'HOME'),
    Flashcard(index:22,
       TF_flag: false,
  question:'To draw a red line in LOGO, you will type  ',
  option1:'PPT 4',
  option2:'SETPC4',
  option3:'SETPC',
  option4:'SETPC 4',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'SETPC4'),
  Flashcard(index:23,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'What does the PU command do? ',
  option1:'It draws a curved line',
  option2:'It is used to lift up the pen of the turtle',
  option3:'It changes colour to blue',
  option4:'None of these',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'It is used to lift up the pen of the turtle'),
Flashcard(index:24,
   TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which of these commands changes the colour of the PEN? ',
  option1:'SETPC',
  option2:'HOME',
  option3:'SETH',
  option4:'PENERASE',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'SETPC'),
  Flashcard(index:25,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which of these commands hides the turtle ? ',
  option1:'HT',
  option2:'PRINT',
  option3:'SETPC',
  option4:'HIDE',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'HT'),
    Flashcard(index:26,
     TF_flag: true,
  question:'The operating System was introduced in the third generation computers ',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'True'),
   Flashcard(index:27,
     TF_flag: true,
  question:'The second generation computers used vacuum tubes ',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'False'),
   Flashcard(index:28,
     TF_flag: true,
  question:'Computers can give accurate results even if the input is incorrect ',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'False'),
   Flashcard(index:29,
     TF_flag: true,
  question:'The Analytical Engine was capable of performing all arithmetic operations ',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'True'),
     Flashcard(index:30,
     TF_flag: false,
  question:'What is Abacus?',
  option1:'Calculating device to do simple calculations like addition and subtraction',
  option2:'A supercomputer',
  option3:'Mobile device ',
  option4:'None of these',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Calculating device to do simple calculations like addition and subtraction'),
  Flashcard(index:30,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'What is Abacus?',
  option1:'Calculating device to do simple calculations like addition and subtraction',
  option2:'A supercomputer',
  option3:'Mobile device ',
  option4:'None of these',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Calculating device to do simple calculations like addition and subtraction'),
    Flashcard(index:31,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'A computer can understand only ?',
  option1:'English language',
  option2:'Programming Language',
  option3:'Binary Language',
  option4:'Regional Language',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Binary Language'),
    Flashcard(index:32,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'1024 KB = ______?',
  option1:'1 Terabyte',
  option2:'1 Megabyte',
  option3:'1 Petabyte ',
  option4:'1 Gigabyte',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'1 Megabyte'),
  Flashcard(index:33,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Secondary storage device used in earlier days was',
  option1:'Floppy Disk',
  option2:'DVD',
  option3:'Pen Drive',
  option4:'Hard disk',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Floppy Disk'),
  Flashcard(index:34,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Digital camera and mobile phones use _______ to store data',
  option1:'Hard disk',
  option2:'Memory card',
  option3:'Pen Drive',
  option4:'Memory',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Memory card'),

  Flashcard(index:35,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Expand USB',
  option1:'Universal Serial Bus',
  option2:'Universal Storage Bus',
  option3:'Universal Storage Bit',
  option4:'None of these',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Universal Serial Bus'),
  Flashcard(index:36,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Expand CD-R',
  option1:'Compact Disc Readable',
  option2:'Compact Disk Recordable',
  option3:'Compact Disk Rewritable',
  option4:'None of these',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Compact Disk Recordable'),
  Flashcard(index:37,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Arrange the following memory units in ascending order - MB, KB, Bit, GB, Byte',
  option1:'MB, KB, Bit, GB, Byte',
  option2:'KB, MB, Bit, GB, Byte',
  option3:'Byte, KB, Bit, MB, GB',
  option4:'Bit, Byte, KB, MB, GB',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Bit, Byte, KB, MB, GB'),
  Flashcard(index:38,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Diya''s sister wants to store 200MB data for a class project. What storage device would be suitable?',
  option1:'Floppy Disk',
  option2:'DVD',
  option3:'CD',
  option4:'Hard disk',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'DVD'),
    Flashcard(index:39,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'What storage device would be suitable to store 20MB of data?',
  option1:'Floppy Disk',
  option2:'DVD',
  option3:'CD',
  option4:'Hard disk',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'CD'),
      Flashcard(index:40,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'What storage device would be suitable to store 500GB of data?',
  option1:'Floppy Disk',
  option2:'DVD',
  option3:'CD',
  option4:'Hard disk',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Hard disk'),
        Flashcard(index:41,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which among these has higher storage capacity?',
  option1:'Blu Ray Disc',
  option2:'DVD',
  option3:'CD',
  option4:'Hard disk',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Hard disk'),
      Flashcard(index:42,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which of these units is smaller than a Giga Byte?',
  option1:'MegaByte',
  option2:'TeraByte',
  option3:'PetaByte',
  option4:'ExaByte',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'MegaByte'),
      Flashcard(index:43,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The result of processing the instruction is seen in the _______ device',
  option1:'Input',
  option2:'Output',
  option3:'Storage',
  option4:'Memory',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Output'),
        Flashcard(index:44,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'A computer uses memory to store data and ____________',
  option1:'Instructions',
  option2:'Invitation',
  option3:'Information',
  option4:'Intimation',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Instructions'),
          Flashcard(index:45,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Storage device present inside the computer is called ____________',
  option1:'CPU',
  option2:'CD',
  option3:'Hard Disk',
  option4:'Pen drive',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Hard Disk'),
  Flashcard(index:46,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Main memory is directly accessible to the  ____________',
  option1:'CPU',
  option2:'Monitor',
  option3:'Printer',
  option4:'Keyboard',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'CPU'),
    Flashcard(index:47,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Data in  ____________ does not get erased even after a power shutdown',
  option1:'RAM',
  option2:'ROM',
  option3:'CPU',
  option4:'Printer',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'ROM'),
      Flashcard(index:48,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Operating system is loaded from the ________',
  option1:'BIOS',
  option2:'CPU',
  option3:'RAM',
  option4:'Monitor',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'BIOS'),
        Flashcard(index:49,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Esha saves a file on her computer. The file gets saved in  ________',
  option1:'RAM',
  option2:'Hard Disk',
  option3:'ROM',
  option4:'DVD',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Hard Disk'),
  Flashcard(index:50,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'How many bytes are there in these bits? 1011 0110 1101 0101',
  option1:'2 bytes',
  option2:'4 bytes',
  option3:'8 bytes',
  option4:'1 byte',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'2 bytes'),
Flashcard(index:51,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Aditi was drawing on MS Paint on her computer. Suddenly there was a power failure. Her drawing got erased from - ',
  option1:'Hard disk',
  option2:'RAM',
  option3:'ROM',
  option4:'CD',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'RAM'),
    Flashcard(index:52,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Write this in binary digits :  ON ON OFF OFF ON OFF  ',
  option1:'110010',
  option2:'001101',
  option3:'101010',
  option4:'110101',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'110010'),
   Flashcard(index:53,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Primary Memory: RAM :: Secondary Memory: ___________',
  option1:'CPU',
  option2:'Pen Drive',
  option3:'Keyboard',
  option4:'Monitor',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Pen Drive'),
     Flashcard(index:54,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'ROM: Read-Only :: RAM: ______________ ',
  option1:'Read-Write',
  option2:'Readable',
  option3:'Writable',
  option4:'Volatile',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Read-Write'),
       Flashcard(index:55,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Internal Memory: Main Memory :: External Memory :  ',
  option1:'Secondary Memory',
  option2:'Primary Memory',
  option3:'CPU',
  option4:'Tertiary Memory',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'Secondary Memory'),
  Flashcard(index:56,
    TF_flag: true,
  question:'The PU command is used to leave gaps in drawings  ',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'True'),
   Flashcard(index:57,
    TF_flag: true,
  question:'The PPT command is used to calcel the PE command  ',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'True'),
     Flashcard(index:58,
    TF_flag: true,
  question:'You can only draw black lines in LOGO ',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'False'),
       Flashcard(index:59,
    TF_flag: true,
  question:'The turtle can draw lines even when it is hidden',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'True'),
  Flashcard(index:60,
    TF_flag: true,
  question:'The PPT command is used to change the erase mode to the paint mode',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'True'),
  Flashcard(index:61,
    TF_flag: true,
  question:'You can only draw squares with the help of the REPEAT command',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'False'),
    Flashcard(index:62,
    TF_flag: true,
  question:'The turtle should be turned through a total of 360 units to draw a circle',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'True'),
    Flashcard(index:63,
    TF_flag: true,
  question:'The REPEAT command can be used only maximum of 5 times',
  option1:'True',
  option2:'False',
  option3:'',
  option4:'',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'False'),
      Flashcard(index:64,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'When you start drawing in MS Logo, the pen is always in this mode',
  option1:'PE',
  option2:'PD',
  option3:'PU',
  option4:'PC',
  //answer:'TeraByte'),
  answer:'PD'),
       Flashcard(index:65,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which of these REPEAT commands will draw a triangle?',
  option1:'REPEAT 3[FD 100 RT 90]',
  option2:'REPEAT 3[FD 100 RT 60]',
  option3:'REPEAT 3[FD 100 RT 120]',
  option4:'REPEAT 4[FD 100 RT 40]',
  answer:'REPEAT 3[FD 100 RT 120]'),
    Flashcard(index:66,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'Which of these commands clears the recall list box?',
  option1:'CT',
  option2:'CS',
  option3:'ERASE',
  option4:'PC',
   answer:'CT'),
    Flashcard(index:67,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'We type LOGO commands in the ________ box?',
  option1:'Recall ',
  option2:'Input',
  option3:'Main Screen',
  option4:'Output',
   answer:'Input'),
       Flashcard(index:68,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The SETH command turns the turtle ______ ',
  option1:'Right ',
  option2:'Left',
  option3:'Center',
  option4:'Same position',
   answer:'Right'),
  Flashcard(index:69,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The command to move the turtle in the forward direction: ',
  option1:'BK ',
  option2:'FD',
  option3:'RT',
  option4:'LT',
   answer:'FD'),
     Flashcard(index:70,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The command to move the turtle in the backward direction: ',
  option1:'BK ',
  option2:'FD',
  option3:'RT',
  option4:'LT',
   answer:'BK'),
     Flashcard(index:71,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The command to move the turtle in the clockwise direction: ',
  option1:'BK ',
  option2:'FD',
  option3:'RT',
  option4:'LT',
   answer:'RT'),
        Flashcard(index:72,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The command to move the turtle in the anti-clockwise direction: ',
  option1:'BK ',
  option2:'FD',
  option3:'RT',
  option4:'LT',
   answer:'LT'),
        Flashcard(index:73,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The command to clear the main screen and move the turtle to the center of the screen: ',
  option1:'CS ',
  option2:'CLEAN',
  option3:'HOME',
  option4:'CT',
   answer:'CS'),
           Flashcard(index:74,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The command to clear the main screen and not change position of the turtle: ',
  option1:'CS ',
  option2:'CLEAN',
  option3:'HOME',
  option4:'CT',
   answer:'CLEAN'),
              Flashcard(index:75,
    TF_flag: false,
  question:'The command to remove the text from Recall list box: ',
  option1:'CS ',
  option2:'CLEAN',
  option3:'HOME',
  option4:'CT',
   answer:'CT'),
];


